Contact

hsaini734@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/dare-rider (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Ruby on Rails Go

Web Applications

Harpreet Singh

Full Stack Engineer at Rakuten Viki Southern

Summary

Software Engineer with 8 years experience.

Consistently improving by working with but not limited to REST, Ruby, Rails, GoLang, Javascript, Redis, Queue Infrastructures - Sidekiq & RabbitMQ, AWS, GCP, ETCD, APM and distributed tracing using Jaeger with New Relic and Datadog.

Experience leading small teams backed by agile sprint methodologies.

- Stacks : Ruby, Rails, GoLang, NodeJS
- Datastores : Mysql, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Front End: EmberJS, ReactJS, BackboneJS
- Monitor & Alert : StatsD, SignalFx, New Relic, Datadog, PagerDuty, Opsgenie.
- Ansible, Terraform, Apache, Nginx (L7 LoadBalancer), AWS, GCP,
 Docker, Kubernetes, Redis, Sidekiq, RabbitMq, Capistrano, Elastic
 Search, Kibana, ETCD

Experience

Rakuten Viki Senior Full Stack Engineer August 2020 - Present (8 months) Singapore

- Structured logging using lograge and logstash, APM and Distributed tracing using DataDog.
- Maintaining GCP CI/CD pipelines for Central and Edge GCP Kubernetes clusters.
- Working on core product features as part of Internal Tools & Workflows team developed in Rails 4, Golang, and EmberJS.

Circles.Life 2 years 1 month Staff Engineer January 2020 - August 2020 (8 months) Singapore

Senior Software Engineer August 2018 - January 2020 (1 year 6 months) Singapore

Worked on HLD, Schema Design, LLD and Implementation of:

- Shop (Order Management Service) Platform with multiple custom State Machine Workflows to support variety of product purchases using GoLang.
- Inventory Management Platform (IMS) with Product Catalog to deal with organisation wide Telco & Non Telco products using GoLang.
- Slot Based logistics micro-service using Rails 5.
- Cart Platform integrated with User Service & IMS using GoLang.

Directed and worked with a sub team of 4 to grow above in-house products using agile sprint methodologies via Atlassian Jira.

Integration of micro services (GoLang & Rails) with ETCD server for runtime configuration updates.

Implemented a Rails based shared cache mechanism using Redis to drop network calls between Logistics and OMS.

Rails based automated models association handling using meta-programming from existing monolith to various micro-services.

StudyPad Senior Software Engineer April 2018 - July 2018 (4 months) Gurgaon, India

Worked on some core product features developed in Rails 4,
Initiated the User Authentication micro-service using Rails 5 after studying
various protocols like Oauth, JWT, Application Gateway, Shared sessions etc.

LearningBlocks (Former 100Percentile) (Nagarro Subsidiary) 4 years 6 months

Tech lead

January 2017 - April 2018 (1 year 4 months) Gurgaon, India

- Worked with and lead a team of 4 for the growth of in-house products.
- Leap LMS is a SAAS based e-learning platform Design and Implemented from scratch initially and then in team as lead using Rails4 backed by Mysql.
- Vlyop is a guided learning platform Design and Implemented from scratch using Rails4 backed by Mysql.
- Deployment on Google cloud and Amazon EC2 servers via Capistrano.

- Used Amazon and Google cloud services like ElasticTranscoder, S3, CloudFront, SES, GCM, Firebase.
- CCAvenue/PayTM/PayUMoney Payment gateway integration.
- BackboneJS, RequireJS, Bootstrap for frontend.
- RFID device integration over TCP.
- FlowPlayer, JwPlayer Integration

Software Engineer

November 2013 - December 2016 (3 years 2 months)

Gurgaon, India

Goldfinch Mobile Solutions Pvt.Ltd. Intern Software Developer July 2013 - September 2013 (3 months) Chandigarh Area, India

Worked on Email/SMS notification engine, Product Features using Java

Education

Kurukshetra University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2009 - 2013)

GMSSS - 16, Chandigarh

Senior Secondary, Metriculation · (2003 - 2009)